Timo Huennebeck

Moving to Melbourne, VIC, AUS in Feb. 2023.

Email: hello@timohuennebeck.comLinkedIn: __/timo-huennebeckPhone: +49 176 86094246Portfolio: __/timohuennebeck.com

German Front End Developer with a penchant for creating digital products that aim to bridge the gap between artificial intelligence and software development in order to create intuitive and seamless user experiences. Loves Tennis too!

FEATURED PROJECTS

ALIA Cologne, GER

Internal Social Media For Companies

November 2022 - Present

- Developed an internal social media tool using React.js, Node.js, Express.js, and Heroku which aims to increase the engagement between remote workers in order to build deeper relationships in a remote environment.
- Likewise aims to implement algorithms and Open Al's artificial intelligence to provide personalised user experiences.

JARVIS Cologne, GER

Cover Letter Automation Tool

October 2022 - Present

- Designed a wireframe using Figma and developed a minimum viable product version of this Full-Stack React app, using Node.js, Express.js, Tailwind, AuthO and Heroku within just one week.
- Presented this app to 50+ alumni and was offered beta testing opportunities from 8+ different BrainStation graduates.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PROSPECT ADVERTISING Mérida, MX

Founder

November 2021 - August. 2022

June 2021 - November 2021

- o Invented a semi-automated sales automation pipeline, which translated to an 11.75% decrease in time required for reaching out to potential leads utilising Pipedrive, Zapier and Lemlist.
- Identified and executed improvements for lead generation, increasing cold email CTR from .85 to 3.15% using Loom.

AMAZON Liverpool, GB

Amazon FBA Seller

o Imported, and launched an SKU from China into the US market, scaling it to USD 2,500 in MRR.

 Developed and executed a post-purchase automation sequence using Facebook messenger, increasing product review submission rates from .45 to 1.35%.

EDUCATION

BRAINSTATION Remote, Toronto, CA

Diploma, Web Development

August 2022 - November 2022

- o Immersive, project-based, 12-week diploma program in web development, including 3 hackathons, and 5 projects all while picking up a multitude of new languages such as JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js and Heroku.
- Collaborated on a 24-hour hackathon with 2 UX designers, 1 data scientist and 1 web developer following an AGILE workflow, utilising stand-ups and team management softwares in order to create an MVP and present it to Microsoft.

UNIVERSITY OF LIVERPOOL Liverpool, GB

International Business (BA) Hons

September 2019 - June 2021

 Designed, developed and presented a marketing plan with four other students using the AIDA framework for a fictional low-calorie ice cream brand and pitched it to 20+ international business students and lecturers.

SKILLS

- Proficient in React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Knex.js, JavaScript, Heroku, Auth0, MySQL and functional knowledge in TypeScript and Tailwind.
- o Native German speaker. Fluent in English (C1) and intermediate (B1) in Spanish.
- o Interests: Tennis, Surfing and Artificial Intelligence.